99% of people are not willing to do, what it takes make their dreams come true.
The Marines have a saying: "Everybody wants to go to heaven, but nobody wants to die"
The center of bringing any dream into fruition is self discipline
You know, something as simple as food and eating... it's not about your body as much as it is about your mind.
It's getting command of your mind to be able to choose actions that are in your own best interest.
Every day we are choosing shit that's not in our own best interest.
So if the world is attacking you and the world wants to fight you and the world's trying to hold you down.
So you're gonna kick yourself in the balls.
So you will stop yourself from getting what you dream.
And I think the word "discipline" has kind of gotten a bad name.
We think about it in terms of punishment.
I'm not talking about discipline in that way.
I'm talking about discipline in the sense that you you forego immediate pleasure
for the exchange of long-term self-respect.
I believe that self-discipline is the definition of self-love
that when you say that you love yourself
that means that you have behavior towards yourself.
That is loving
Self-discipline is the center of all material success.
You cannot win the war against the world if you can't win the war against your own mind.
Self-love is when you say to yourself
Man, look I know you and that girl got a real connection
I know y'all vibe, but
Yes, your girl's cousin. So I love you too much to let you do that
It's like you say to yourself a man look
I know you want to eat that pizza and it'll be really good, you know, but I can't let you eat that man
cuz if you eat that pizza, you're gonna feel like
You know, and I I just I love you too much to let you eat that
Self-love is a look. I know you got a a test on Monday, you know
and I know you really want to go out with your friends and Saturday night you want to go out but
If you fail that test, you're not gonna feel good about yourself
You know, I just I love you too much to let you go out tonight
Self-discipline is
Self-love if you wanna be happy you have to love yourself
Which means you have to discipline your behavior
the road
Sustained
happiness is through
Disciplining your behavior. We tend to base our self-esteem
on what other people think and
That's not really
Self-esteem self-esteem asposed to be how we feel about ourselves
and I was just saying how dangerous it is to
allow other people to determine how you're going to feel about you and it's kind of like
looking into a broken mirror.
You're gonna look in a broken mirror and then change your face to try to look good in this defiled busted
broken mirror and
it just other people's opinions. There's a really shit way to determine how we feel about
ourselves.
It don't matter whose fault it is that something is broken if it's your responsibility to fix it
For example, it's not somebody's fault if their father was an abusive alcoholic.
But it's for damn sure their responsibility
to figure out how they're gonna do with those traumas and try to make a life out of it
It's not your fault if your partner cheated and ruined your marriage
But it is for damn sure your responsibility to figure out how to take that pain and how to overcome that and build a happy life for yourself.
Fault and responsibility do not go together. It sucks, but they don't.
When something is somebody's fault we want them to suffer.
We want them punished. We want them to pay. We want it to be their responsibility to fix it
but that's not how it works, especially when it's your heart.
Your heart, your life, your happiness is your responsibility and your responsibility alone
As long as we're pointing the finger and stuck in whose fault
Something is we're jammed and trapped into victim mode when you're in victim mode
You're stuck in suffering the road to power is in taking responsibility
Your heart your life your happiness is your responsibility and your responsibility alone
Do you make a person smile you can make a person feel good you can make a person laugh
but whether or not a person is happy is
Deeply and totally and utterly out of your control
The prerequisite for spending time with any person is that they nourish and inspire you
They feed your flame. Look at your last five text messages.
Are those people feeding your flames or dousing your fire?
Put your phone down for just a second and look around
Look to the people around you
Are those people throwing logs on your fire or they pissing on it?
I want my life, I want my work, my family.
I wanted to mean something and it's like it has if you are not making someone else's life better than you're wasting your time.
The separation of talent and skill is one of the the the greatest misunderstood concepts for people who are trying to excel who have dreams that want to do things.
Talent you have naturally. Skill is only developed by hours and hours and hours of beating on your craft.
You don't try to build a wall
You don't set out to build a wall. You don't say I'm the biggest, baddest, greatest wall that's ever been built.
You don't start there. You say I'm gonna lay this brick as perfectly as a brick can be laid.
There will not be one brick on the face of the earth that's gonna be lay better than this brick; that I'm gonna lay in this next 10 minutes.
And you do that every single day.
And soon you have a wall and I think psychologically
the advantage that that gives me over over a lot of people that I
have been in competition with in different situations is
it's difficult to take the first step when you look how big
the task
The definition of Who I am is very clear to me and it also
redefines who I want to be
in that I
know for a fact that
I'm stronger than I thought I was you know, you can't help but ask yourself the question. What would I do if I was in?
Mohammed Eileen shoes
I'm motivated by fear. I
hate
Scared abuse on
And I think what developed
Was the the attitude that I started attacking things
I was scared
Why were you scared in your bed the night before?
Why did you what do you need that fear for just don't go?
Why are you scared in your bed 16 hours before you jump? Why are you scared in the car?
Why could you not enjoy breakfast?
fear is
Fear of what you're nowhere near the airplane if we think up to the stepping out
There's actually no reason to be scared. It only just ruins your day
You're you don't have to jump and then in that moment all of a sudden where you should be terrified is the most blissful
Experience of your life and God place the best things in life on the other side of terror