I'm here to talk about success right
[Applause]
[Music]
the first rule of success is to have a
vision you see if you don't have a
vision of where you go and if you don't
have a goal where you go you drift
around and you never end up anywhere
it's like you can have the best ship in
the world
you can have the best airplane in the
world if the pilot or the captain
doesn't know where to go
it would just drift around they would
not end up anywhere almost like in the
wrong place so I was very fortunate did
I stumble on the my vision I mean as you
know I was born in 1947 in Austria after
the Second World War and I didn't really
like Austria when I grew up I couldn't
wait to get out of there I couldn't see
myself becoming a farmer or working in a
factory or anything like that even
though my parents wanted me to stay
there and have a normal life my father
wanted me to become a police officer
like he was my mother wanted me just to
stay there and marry a girl in the name
of Heidi hopefully and have a bunch of
kids and run around like the fun trap
family in the sound of music but that
was their vision not mine my vision was
totally different I felt that that was
born for something special for something
unique for something big do you know how
great it felt that I knew where I was
going
imagine the majority of people don't
know where they're going
it's when you have a goal when you have
a vision everything becomes easy
because remember that in America for
instance when you study you will see the
percentage of people did like their jobs
[Music]
74% hate their job in America
now this is not much different when you
come to Europe the majority of people
don't like what they're doing because
they're really not doing it because they
didn't have a goal and they'd followed
this goal they're just aimlessly drift
around and then over sudden if there's a
job opening so they get their job
because if the world but then when you
grow it's a chore it's work it's not fun
so if you think about only a quarter of
the people really enjoy what they're
doing in life that is unbelievable if
you think about it so I felt so blessed
that I knew what I was doing
it's like a medical students in studies
and knows he wants to become a doctor
you know where to go
so I know where to go so people always
ask me when they saw me in the gym in
the pumping iron days you say why is it
that you're working out so hard five
hours a day six hours a day and you have
always a smile on your face the others
are working out just as hard as you do
and then look sour
in the face why is that and they told
people all the time is it because to me
I am shooting for gold in front of mr.
mr. Universe title so every rep that I
do gets me closer to accomplishing that
goal to make this call this vision turn
into reality every single set that I do
every repetition every weight that the
lift will get my step closer to turned
his goal into reality so I couldn't wait
to do another 500 pound squat I couldn't
wait to another 500 pound bench press I
couldn't wait to do another 2,000 reps
of sit-ups I couldn't wait for the next
exercise for the next half hour posing
and all the kind of things that you have
to do you'll be a champion and with the
age of 20
with the age of 20 I went to London and
I won the Mr Universe contest as the
youngest mr. universe ever and it was
because I had a goal so let me tell you
something visualizing your goal and
going after it makes it fun you got to
have a purpose no matter what you do in
life you got to have a purpose so that's
rule number one
have a vision rule number two is don't
listen to the naysayers don't listen to
the naysayers everything I ever did the
thing that they heard out of people's
mouths was that's impossible that can't
be done
Oh No so whenever someone said to me it
can't be done I heard it can be done
when they say no I heard yes I mean they
said it's impossible I heard it is
possible I'm a strong believer what
Nelson Mandela said that everything is
always impossible until someone does it
well I'm gonna be the one that said to
myself I'm gonna do it and I'm gonna
show you to them maybe it has never been
done before that's perfectly fine with
me but I am gonna do it and I did not
listen to the naysayers
next thing the third point that I'm
gonna make to you is before we sit down
with your gun and talk about the rest of
the three is work your ass off there is
no magic bill there is no magic out
there you cannot get around you have to
work and work and work and it drives me
crazy when people say they don't have
enough time to go to the gym for 45
minutes a day and work out or do
something for 45 minutes to an hour they
do improve if it is physically improve
of it is mentally to improve imagine you
read one hour a day about history how
much you will learn after 365 hours in
one year think about if you study about
the history of musicians of composers
how much you would know
imagine if you who work on the business
and some business that you want to
develop every day for an hour
imagine how further along you will go
and get
so it drives me nuts because we have but
people said we don't have the time we
have 24 hours a day we sleep 6 hours a
day so that gives you still 18 hours
and there's someone shaking the head out
here in front to say probably I don't
sleep six hours i sleep eight hours
right but just sleep faster
[Applause]
so we have 18 hours a day the average
person works around 8 to 10 hours so
let's assume it's 10 hours so if you
have 8 hours left then you travel around
an hour a day maybe 2 hours a day
so now you've still 6 hours left so what
do you do with this 6 hours
where do we the six hours then we eat a
little bit and we schmooze a little bit
talk a little bit the people in ordered
stuff but you can see how much time 2 is
available if you organize your day so
you got to work hard I mean let me tell
you something when I went to America I
went to college I went and worked out 5
hours a day and I was working on
construction because in those days in
bodybuilding there was no money we
didn't I didn't have the money for food
supplements or anything so I had to go
to work so we worked in construction I
went to college I worked out in the gym
and at night from 8 o'clock at night to
12 midnight I went to acting class four
times a week say I did all that there
was not one single minute that I wasted
I became very friendly with Muhammad Ali
in the 70s Muhammad Ali worked his butt
off in a saw it firsthand now remember
that there was a sports rider that was
there in the gym when he was working out
and he was doing situps
and they asked him how many sit-ups do
you do and he said I don't start
counting until it hurts now think about
that he doesn't start counting his
sit-ups and bill Davy feels pain that's
when he starts counting that is working
hard and so you can't get around the
hardware it doesn't matter who it is so
maverick I believe what Ted Turner said
work like hell and advertise
you get it work like hell go to bed and
early early to rise work like hell and
advertise so you work your ass off and
then you let the world know about your
work that's what it is all about let
people know if you have a company if you
have a movie if you do a sports work
your ass off but then advertise and let
everyone know I hate plan B and I tell
you why because we have so many doubters
as I've said earlier they eat the no
sales we have so many of those people
did say no and you can't do it it's
impossible that is okay because we just
turn off as I said earlier and B listen
and be hear that now being a yes you
can't do it do it you can't do it and
all that so that that is possible to do
that amongst all the negative people
around you but when you start doubting
yourself that's very dangerous because
now what you're basically saying is is
that if my plan doesn't work
I have a fallback plan have a plan B if
that means that you start thinking about
Plan B and every thought that you put
into Plan B you're taking away now that
thought and that energy from plan a and
and it's very important to understand
that we function better if there is no
safety net because Plan B becomes a
safety net it says that if I fail then
fr and I get picked up and I have
something else there that was they will
protect me and that's not good because
people perform better when there is no
safety net people perform better in
sports and everything else if you don't
have a plan B to me it is very dangerous
to have a plan B because you're cutting
yourself off from the chance of really
succeeding and the reason one of the
main reasons why people want to have a
plan B is because they are worried about
failing
what is if I fail then I don't have
anything else well let me tell you
something don't be afraid of failing
because there's nothing wrong with
failing you have to fail in order to
climb that ladder there's no one that
doesn't fail
we all fail it's okay
what is not okay is that when you fail
you stay down whoever stays down is a
loser and winners will fail and get up
fail and get up fail and get up you
always get up that is a winner that is a
winner
hey we all lose you all have lost us
this is okay and this is why I say don't
be worried about losing because when
you're afraid of losing then you get
frozen you get stiff you're not relaxed
you got to be in order to perform well
in anything if it's in boxing or if it
is on your job or with your thinking is
only happening when you relax so relax
it's okay to fail let's just go all out
and give it everything that you got
that's what it is all about so don't be
afraid to fail this is one of my six
rules to success you can only feel
complete as a person
if you think about what can you do for
your fellow member around you that maybe
needs help
I felt like that everyone has a
different motivation why you get into
that I was an immigrant going to America
and I saw how America was the most
generous country in the world I mean
they opened up their arms to me they
helped me they invited me for
Thanksgiving dinner the people they
brought me the bodybuilders in the gym
brought me plates to my apartment
because I had no plates had no
silverware
I had no bed where I had no pillows at
no blanket I had no TV I had no radio I
had nothing they brought it to my
apartment
they helped me that's all that firsthand
this generosity in America in the city
myself as an immigrant that is being
embraced with open arms that I need to
go and make sure that I give something
back
[Music]